Objective: Three year experienced data and systems analyst and five year experienced election and campaign management professional tailoring enterprise digital and political analytic, predictive, and operational skills in value extension and exchange across dimensionality reduction, un-/supervised learn, and survey methods.

Professional History

Kastling Group

Boutique digital and management consulting firm focusing on providing enterprise digital modernization / transformation to federal clients. Reported to the CEO and CTO with engagements with the US House, Office of Legislative Counsel; US House, Office of the Clerk with Xcential; Democracy Fund's BillMap with GovTrack and Xcential, Good2Go with Infuse.

Associate, Data and Systems, 2020 - Present

Responsibilities

- Modeling, engineering, and testing functions, relations, and requirements of United States legislatives processes and behavior in parrallel with technical architecture and interoperations for digital development / transformation and human-centered design projects in an Agile / MBSE, Plant-/UML / Python, and Google Cloud environment.
- Intelligence reporting focusing on sentiment inference and prediction, survey methodology / execution / analysis, and operational metrics in Qualtrics, BigQuery, Azure / Google DataStudio, and Colab.

Accomplishments

- Developed agglomerative clustering model in scikit-learn to describe employee working relationship and attitudes for workload redistribution, process re-engineering, and executive operations planning.
- Developed and implemented employee, client, and user opinion and experience surveying / sampling and relational networking, focus-grouping, and workshopping via Qualtrics and traditional methods.
- Developed and maintained automated functional testing and continuous integration pipeline in Google Cloud, GitHub Actions, and Python / Selenium.

House Caucus Campaign Committee

Caucus political arm of the Pennsylvania State House of Representatives chartered with securing partisan majorities. Directed six- and seven-figure electoral media and polling programs with five direct-reporting and over thirty indirect-reporting field and political staff over two general-, two primary- and six special-election cycles for nationally targeted caucus.

Specialist, Data & Analytics, 2019-2020 Director, Political & Operations, 2017-2018

Responsibilities

- Directed and assisted in planning, execution, testing, and analysis of seven-figure polling, media and field programs.
- Managed staff of 5-30 with varying levels of authority, as well as executive and staff training and instruction.
- Application / database administrator and engineer for >2,000 non/technical users and executive leadership in the VAN at tier III / VII support and 20 users in BigQuery environment at tier II / VII support.

Accomplishments

- Designed, built, and operationalized committee, campaign and executive facing ETL pipelines across federal, state, media, and vendor Python / REST API's and sources with BigQuery / PostgreSQL and Ubuntu Server, analytics and metrics processing $2-5{\rm Gbpd}$ in Python, voter targeting and management to BigQuery-Phoenix / the VAN, and interactive reporting and dashboards in PostgreSQL / BigQuery, DataStudio and Colab / Bokeh.
- Voter targeting and contact and media operations resulting in up to 16% increase in voting probability.
- Developed random forest classifier to mid 80% accuracy scores to measure preference volatility of voters, in addition to operational optimizations, and prioritizations methods and models.

Interim Executive Director, 2019

Responsibilities

- Directed, and managed committee leadership, budget, stakeholders, staff, operations and communications.

Accomplishments

- Successfully executed campaign cycle for two six-figure special elections.

FIRST Global

Consultant, Operations and Logistics, Summer 2017

Responsibilities

- Development and management of six/seven-figure operational / logistic programming and team of 15-20 vendors/consultants in an implementation engagement with the initial annual international robotics competition.

Accomplishments

 Successful completion of six/seven-figure event transportation, housing, and meals for > 2000 competitors from 158 countries and data management solutions for media production team.

PA State House & PA Common Court Campaign Commitee

Campaign Manager; General Election 2016 & Primary Election 2017

Designed and managed six-figure financial, organizational and operational, communications and media, research and polling, field strategies, and staffs of 3-30 for two campaigns in southwestern Pennsylvania—a dual-ballot campaign in cross-partisan primary election, and an incumbent-defense campaign overperforming top-of-ticket for state's top three competitive elections in southwestern Pennsylvania.

Fairfax Board of Supervisors & U.S. Senate Campaign Committee

Organizing Director; 2015 General & 2016 Primary Election

Outback Steakhouse Server, 2012 - 2014

Ravensworth Swim and Racquet Club

Head Coach, Summer 2012

Starbucks

Barista, 2010 - 2012

Sideburn Run Recreation Association

Head Coach, Summer 2009 & 2010

Dominion Dive Club

Assistant Coach, Fall 2008 - Spring 2010

Tools

Analysis

Python (NumPy, scikit-learn, Bokeh, Shapely, NetworkX, Selenium), ArcGIS / ArcMap, Plant-/UML / SysML / MBSE

Data

SQL (BigQuery, Postgres, MS-, T-, Phoenix), Bash, SSH, REST, TLS / SSL, SSH, JSON, XML (USLM), YAML / Markdown, VAN / NGP, Qualtrics, Azure / Google Data Studio

Management

Git, PuTTY, Jira, Asana, Trello, Agile (Scrum, Behavior-Driven), Linux (Ubuntu), Windows, Microsoft Project

Other

vim, IATEX, Google Suite (Docs, Sheets, Slides, API), Adobe (InDesign, Photoshop, Acrobat), LexisNexis, Associate Press / Chicago Style

Other History

fburdell@gmail.com | fburdell.io | github/fburdell | linkedin/fburdell

FieldBlue

Advisor, 2021 - Present

Technical and strategic advice for political technological start-up.

Project Keystone

Board Member & Proxy, 2018 - 2020

Assisted in direction, planning, and distribution of seven-figures in polling and research funds through 501c4/527-hybrid consortium focused on legislative races in Pennsylvania.

Turn Pennsylvania Blue

Volunteer, 2020

Provided data, targeting, and analytic services to volunteer-driven electoral committee.

The OpenElections Project

Volunteer, Winter 2018

Developed Python module to transform and standardize election files from Pennsylvania to specified structure.

U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, Eastern Regional Office

Intern, Summer 2013

Virginia House of Delegates, Office of the Minority Leader

Intern, Fall 2012

Projects

Comparative Print Testing Suite

Automated testing and continuous integration pipeline in Google Cloud, Github Actions, and Python / Selenium.

Partisan Variance Model

Random forest classifier to mid 80% model accuracy scores to measure preference volatility of voters providing voter classifications outperforming comparable models by 4-8%.

Integral Approximation

Approximating 2-dimensional functions given its integral and boundaries.

Education History

Non-Degree Seeking – Harrisburg Area Community College, 2019

Coursework: Calculus I.

BA; Political Theory – University of Virginia, 2012 - 2014

Coursework: Epistemology, Symbolic Logic, Classical Theory, Concepts of Law, Perspectives on Liberty, Contemporary Thought, Contemporary Ethics, Political Economy, Microeconomics I, Macroeconmics I, Statistics I, Physics I.

BA; Candidate - George Mason University, 2010 - 2012

NCAA Div. I, Colonial Athletic Association; Swimming and Diving: 2011 Rookie of the Year.